As we came out of the dark tunnel, we saw...
Yay, the ocean!
Photoshoot time!
Whoa, and there are like, no people here!
Not many people know about it.
Eri and I used it a lot for cosplay shoots.
Let's go to the beach!
I wanna get Nonopi out to the beach.
Otaku don't like going to the beach.
Right, Ririsa-chan?
The beach is a great idea!
Yes, a great idea indeed.
The contrast of our skin
against the brilliant blue!
Dramatic sunlight! Infinite shot angles!
It's the perfect place for a shoot!
Every cosplayer wants to
get pictures on the beach!
And with Obon season over,
and beach season dying down,
now's the perfect time.
Jellyfish season is cosplay season!
Jellyfish season?
I see.
You're thinking an overnight trip, right, Kisaki-san?
An overnighter?!
Yeah! That's the idea!
Well, if it's for cosplay...
A summer training camp trip, huh?
Every sports anime has that episode.
Damn, this is totally gonna make us power up.
So we are treating cosplay as a sport. Thought so.
A sleepover with Senpai. A sleepover with Senpai.
A sleepover with Senpai!
Senpai, my modeling contract says no swimsuits,
but I'll wear one just for you.
Cool, can't wait.
Yeah, yeah, I already know you don't really care!
Wait a second, does Mikarin...
...have a crush on Okumura?
No way. She's a famous fashion model!
Why would she want a weirdo otaku like...
The manga you made, the manga you created...
Like him...
Man, sometimes, 3D girls act so weird
I can't even tell what they're thinking.
Manga Club On the Beach
Girls in swimsuits...
I couldn't care less... But I have to, for the art!
Cosplay isn't 2D or 3D.
At best, it's 2.5D, right in the middle.
They call Erika the closest thing to 2D,
but in my eyes, she's perfectly 2.5D.
Photos are 2D, and you can use editing
magic to make them look even more 2D.
Maybe what you're missing is that
awareness that your cosplayer is a living,
breathing person.
I need to see them as a person?
As long as you see Ririsa as a life-size figurine,
you'll never get a picture of a living, breathing Liliel.
So, I'll never get good photos unless
I develop some kind of interest in 3D girls?
Senpai!
W-what do you think?
I know you couldn't wait to see,
so I'm a little nervous to...
S-senpai?!
No, show some interest, Okumura!
If I want to get lifelike cosplay pictures,
I need to change my mindset!
3D girls aren't figurines!
I-it's okay. I shouldn't have expected you to care.
You look great, Mikari.
After all that, did Senpai just say
I looked good out of cosplay?
Mikari?! Don't die on me!
Did I mess that up?
Hey, don't get ahead of us here, guys!
Mikarin! Okumura!
I bought this just for today!
Though not like you would care that much, Okumura.
No, you look great.
That color matches your bright personality.
Thanks. I'm glad I went for yellow.
Where's that come from?
What happened to him not caring?!
Did I do that right?
Sounds like you're taking my advice to heart, Okamura.
Go on, tell me how I look!
Don't need to.
Hey! Most guys would be thrilled to see their
22-year-old teacher in a tight swimsuit!
Wonder what Ririsa's gonna wear.
Oh, shoot, I should've given her advice.
Bet it'll be a disaster.
Sorry that took so long!
Sorry, I just couldn't get my hair right...
Ririsa, the photoshoot's tomorrow.
Wait, it is?!
I'll go take my wig and wings off!
Senpai, don't go into the light!
I'm so sorry about that!
Now I'm ready.
Why'd my heart leap into my throat?!
Senpai?
Y-yeah, Ririsa, you look cu...
S-s-s-s-senpai, let's go!
Mikari-chan?!
Take this!
And this!
What're you waiting for, Okumura!
Oh, right.
S-senpai, do you, uh... Work out?
Yeah, all otaku work out.
We do the One Punch Man routine,
then the HxH punches of gratitude.
Pretty sure no one actually does those.
Where's Nonoa?
Hey, Nono-pi, come play with us!
What's so fun about splashing
water or throwing a ball?
Nonoa?
You should go be with them.
Okumura-senpai... Sure, but...
There must be a reason why they like it so much.
Why don't you go over there and
see if you can find out why?
I guess I could.
That feels nice.
Nono-pi!
Nonoa-chan!
What are you doing?!
Tossin' the ball around!
The ball's not even here right now!
Isn't this fun?!
Your extrovert energy is kinda intimidating!
But yeah, the water feels nice,
and seeing you guys having so much
fun is kinda rubbing off on me, too.
It's not like coming here
made a difference, though...
Nono-pi!
You're so cute when you're being tsundere!
Hey, the lodge owner gave us a watermelon!
Let's bust it open!
Wow, three melons.
Go for it, Senpai!
It's more to the right! Wait, the left!
Up, up, down, down, left, right, left, right, B, A!
Don't confuse me with random cheat codes!
Here you go, Nonoa-chan!
Thanks.
I'm not a big fan of watermelon.
It reminds me of cucumbers and
how it's not really that sweet.
Plus it's gross that it's red on the inside.
Did a watermelon kill your parents or something?
No, but...
It definitely tastes better with friends.
Go right! Now left!
This isn't how the watermelon game is supposed to work!
Careful, don't let that otaku fool you!
Got any trash?
Yeah, thanks.
Okumura-senpai, you're kinda like a superhero.
Wait, me?
Usually when people talk to me,
they want something out of it,
or just want to talk about themselves.
Most people don't bother asking me what I think,
or trying to help me.
You're the first person who did, Okumura-senpai.
Sorry, was it too much?
No.
I just feel like you truly see me,
in every sense of the word.
And that makes me happy.
It makes me want to spend more time with you.
It does?
She thinks I truly see her?
What makes her feel that way, though?
That's how I make you feel?
Yeah.
That smile.
If I had my camera right now,
this would make a fantastic picture!
Why'd I think that, though?
Did I really just think a 3D girl was cute?
That's it. I just need to puzzle this out.
Thanks, Nonoa.
I'm gonna take some great pictures tomorrow!
Wait a second...
Did I just improve my social link
with Okumura-senpai?!
Maybe this'll unlock a new ending!
I don't think I have to worry about Nonoa.
Ohmigosh, we should totally go on
a night walk somewhere spooky!
Ooh, that'd be fun!
That's such a cliché.
The perfect chance to glom onto Senpai!
Trespassing onto private property
without just cause is illegal.
As your club president,
it's my duty to keep us on the right side of the law!
It's okay, actually.
Landowner Approved!
Abandoned Cemetery Tour
The town tourism board has a legal option.
Hey, Aria, are you scared of ghosts?
They're like the number one thing that scares me!
I saw something! I totally saw something!
It's just a spirit floating around.
You're supposed to say,
'Don't worry, it's nothing!'
Sorry!
That's right.
He doesn't see me that way.
I feel like an idiot for getting embarrassed.
Wow, Aria's usually so strong and confident.
W-what?
She needs my help.
Don't worry. I'm here if you need me.
What the hell?
Okay, well I need you, so...
How is he so good at this?
Did you see her?
She nearly leaped out of her skin!
But the guy with her doesn't
seem affected in the slightest.
We gotta give 'em a good scare
to get more tourists out here!
Yeah!
Look, Sensei, a spirit!
Go easy on her, guys.
Gotta catch 'em all!
Hold on!
Get back here!
I wish I could've been with Senpai.
I totally drew the wrong straw.
Nonoa looks totally chill.
Is she not scared of this stuff?
Don't worry, I've got you.
I can exorcise most low-level spirits.
Whoa... How is she so good at this?
Okay, that is WAY freakier than a dinky floating soul!
It reminds me of those urban legend monsters,
like the kunekune or Hasshaku-sama!
That's too tough for me!
I should ask the high priest what to do next time!
This way! Don't let them see you!
This way!
Definitely not this way!
Still nothing?!
How?!
What's wrong with you, Okumura?!
How are you not scared?!
Do you just not believe in ghosts?!
Huh? No, ghosts totally exist.
Why would I be scared of
something I know is there?
What?
True otaku are always ready
for the supernatural to appear!
I've practiced using superpowers in my mind,
just in case they ever awaken in me.
I'm always prepared to receive a
ghostly visitor and their spiritual assistance!
Otaku are crazy!
You okay, Aria?
I can't move. My legs are like jelly.
Want me to carry you on my back,
or like a princess?
Huh?
Y-you're kidding, right?
You know I'm heavier than most girls.
A-and I'm hardly a princess, so...
Oh, God.
I know this feeling.
I can't deny it anymore.
I've got a crush on him.
Let's wait here for everyone to catch up.
Sure.
Okumura, I bet the girls love you.
What?
You're single, right?
You're not dating Ririsa, or Mikarin?
No?
There aren't any girls you'd wanna date?
Nah, I don't do 3D girls.
Like, never?
Well...
I liked 3D girls when I was little.
There was one girl I liked, too.
Oh, whoa.
But, then my mom hooked up with a
random guy and left me all on my own.
That's when I stopped trusting people.
If they're just gonna betray me,
why bother with them in the first place?
No one thinks much of me, anyways.
Life's easier when you don't care about opinions.
Isn't that hard, though?
Not when I have the 2D world.
It makes life worth living.
It's probably saved my life
a hundred times without me realizing it.
Liliel would never betray me.
She's always been there.
But I guess lately, I'd say...
Wait, are you crying for me?
There are people who deal
with way worse than that!
That doesn't mean your situation sucks any less!
Everyone's lives are a mix of
happy moments and sad moments.
We've all lived through sad moments,
so I know how much it must've hurt for you!
That must have been so hard.
Huh?
Okumura, you're crying.
I am?
I guess no one's ever said that to me before.
I don't know how to feel.
Hey, Okumura.
I would never betray the man I loved.
Yeah, I know you're not that kind of person, Aria.
Lately, I've started to think
that girls like that could exist.
You do, so they must.
Thanks.
Sure.
Hey, you guys okay?
Aww, you guys were behind everything?
Sorry!
That was great.
That big one was really scary!
The wriggly one that was like, three meters tall?
That wasn't ours.
It's time for the photoshoot.
I want to help Ririsa achieve her
dream and make an awesome cosrom...
Not just because I promised her,
but because I genuinely want to help.
Her cosplay is already perfect.
The rest is up to me!
Senpai!
Let's do this!
Yeah!
Let's get started!
Eyes on the camera, everyone!
Liliel, can you come take a look?
Sure, Senpai!
I think they look good, but...
They're so good!
The lighting is harsh, but it works,
considering the location.
What is it, Liliel?
What do you need me to change?
Oh, nothing, Senpai!
The composition, the timing,
everything looks just like the manga!
You can be honest, you know.
I am! I don't see anything that needs fixing.
We're already doing the best we can.
That's right.
We're doing our best,
but I haven't done better yet!
I have to stop thinking
of Liliel as a figurine,
or I won't be able to
capture the real, live Liliel!
I need to tear down this mental wall,
and capture the real, live Liliel in front of me!
Not the 2D, not the 3D,
but the 2.5D Liliel!
Think, dammit! Liliel is your waifu!
You're taking photos of your darling wife!
It's not working!
I can't imagine a world where
I can actually touch my waifu!
Wait, why is Senpai only taking pictures of Liliel?
Why won't you look at me?!
How's your homework coming along?
Looks about the same to me.
Yeah...
This one of Miriella is good.
She feels like a real, live person.
Really?! How, though?
Try figuring it out on your own.
You won't be able to do this again until you do.
Um..
Her face looks pretty?
It's deeper than that, bozo.
But, at least you can
recognize that she looks pretty.
I always could.
I mean, you don't have to be crazy
about flowers to know they're pretty.
Mikari has always been pretty.
I thought she was pretty the day we met.
But...
He'd already given up on
real women around then, huh?
This is tricky.
Something about that hang-up is
stifling his skill as a photographer.
If we could get that figured out on this trip,
it might help him grow as a person, too.
When I saw Miriella in that moment,
I felt something inside.
But what was it?
And back then, and that moment, too...
But what? And why?
Hey guys, Okumura's dying on us.
Let's take a break.
Okay!
Senpai, you okay?
Oh, hey, Miriella.
Wow, you really are out of it.
What's it actually like to have a wife?
Wait, you want to get married already?!
No, I'm just trying something for the shoot.
Oh, huh.
Like, what would it be like
to take pictures of my wife?
Maybe it'd feel something like this?
She's cute, always there for you,
and you feel totally relaxed with her.
Yeah...
I get nervous around Liliel, but right now,
I feel weirdly calm and relaxed.
Is it because the person in the
cosplay is my childhood friend?
Hey, sleepyhead.
How long was I out?
About two hours.
Huh?!
It's fine. Everyone's having fun outside.
Wait, were you here the whole two hours?
Yeah, you looked cute.
Sorry.
Don't apologize.
I can hold out for two hours.
I've held out for ten years already.
Huh?
Nothing.
For a second, I saw Mikari inside of Miriella.
That's it.
This 2D angel didn't come
down from heaven on her own!
Mikari brought her down to earth!
It's the cosplayer!
Senpai!
You have to hear what Aria-chan told us!
She... She saw a sea cucumber and...
Guys! You promised you wouldn't tell anyone!
Now you have to tell us.
Senpai... When did you start
looking at other girls like that?
He's never looked at me like that.
Mikari-chan?
Is she crying?
Senpai lights up every time Ririsa enters the room.
It's only a matter of time now.
Mikari-chan, are you okay?
Leave me alone.
But...
Just go!
I'm your friend,
I can't let you cry out here alone!
What's wrong?!
I love him!
I'm in love with Senpai.
2.5-Dimensional Ririsa